Philip

https://github.com/



#### Personal Statement

I am an adaptable engineer with 7+ years computing experience, who loves working on a great diversity of domain problems. My work history spans both products and research in machine learning, software engineering, and computer securities. I have successfully adopted new technologies/languages for nearly every completed deliverable.

### Skills/Experience :

Python C, C++ Linux TDD R, dplyr ETFX Git Ticketing Systems

## Work Experience \_

Graduate Research

Researched deep anomaly detectors, to index bioacoustic events from a 10 year audio track Measured effects of adaptive spectral subtraction for audio denoising on model accuracy Developed , an intuitive track explorer, to rejuvenate data access for researchers Technologies: Python, Keras, tensorflow, scipy.signal, Jupyter

- Staff Software Engineer March 2019 - present Worked as software developer in nimble small team in both a remote and onsite environment

Worked as software developer in nimble small team in both a remote and onsite environment Developed , a cross platform tablet application for managing citizen-science projects Maintained and contributed to user tools for identification and tracking Technologies: NativeScript, Angular, node.js, Android, PostgreSQL

- Graduate Data Science Intern June 2018 - Sept. 2018
Fully specified programmatic solution from use-case meetings with top employees
Designed & developed Expert Modeling/Recommender System, by extending the Author-Topic-Model
Implemented stable/principled text normalization, tokenization, and model evaluation
Open Source contributions to the

Technologies : Python, nltk, gensim, pyLDAvis, pandas, Jupyter

Research Assistant

Oct. 2017 - June 2018

Contributed to microbiome population analytics tools, to study female reproductive system

Developed processing pipeline and audit tools for reported and FMRI data, on AHDH/ASD studies

Acted as OSS and Securities lead, developing, training and enforcing best practices

Technologies: Python, Bash, R, neo4j, ponyorm, stan, GitLab, Docker

(Part Time) - Contractor/Consultant Nov. 2015 - Aug. 2018

Developed custom photo image processing tools and pipelines for low cost spectral analysis

Authored educational material in light pollution's effect on economy, biology, and technology

Developed natural language processing tools to organize and explore Myeloma clinical trials

Provided technology tutorials and consulting on code optimization, NLP, and image processing

Technologies : Python, numpy, skimage, AWS, PostgreSQL

#### Research Engineer

April 2014 - Dec 2015

Developed processing pipelines and workflows to enable evaluator work for programs
Helped run professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages
Produced biannual quantitative and qualitative reports on for and language developers
Contributed to professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

A produced biannual quantitative and qualitative reports on for professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages

The professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic professional trainings to disseminate new professional trainings to disseminate new professional trainings to disseminate new professional trainings to disseminate

Technologies : Python, SLURM, Scala, , , , Docker, Jira, Basecamp

# Neato Projects \_\_\_\_\_

Topic modeling and applications, a presentation for non-statisticians beamer, ETEX
Workshop collaborative introduction to GitHub and slides markdown, bash, github.api
Distributed Morphological Watersheding Algorithms pyspark, numpy, ndimage, Python
Distributed Fully Homomorphic Encryption System
Concurrent Elliptic Curve Cryptography Module
Sagemath, Erlang

## Education

## University

## Machine Learning

Computer Science MSc

#### Courses :

Analysis of Sequences
Artificial Intelligence
Computing Ethics
Deep Learning
Image Processing
Information Retrieval
Problem Solving with Large Clusters

### University

Computer Science BS, Mathematics Minor

## Computer Science & Cryptography

Machine Learning, Advanced Topics

Univariate Statistical Analysis

Signal Processing, Advanced Topics

Natural Language Processing

Signal Processing, Speech

Machine Learning

Statistical Methods

#### Electives :

Abstract Algebra
Artificial Intelligence
Computer Architecture
Computer Graphics
Cryptography & Elliptic Curves
Elementary Real Analysis

Functional Programming
Homomorphic Encryption Systems
Linear Algebra I/II
Natural Language Processing
Number Theory
Ordinary Differential Equations